How do I get to library? 
Where is the nearest post office? 
Can you tell me the way to the Big Hotel? 
Are we on the right road for London? 
Can you Show me on the map, please? 
I’m looking for this address. 
How do I find…? 
Excuse me, How can I go to …? 
Dou you have a map? 
Are you from around here? 
Where is …? 
Which the best way to …? 
Pardon me, I’m lost, how do I get to …? 
I’m looking for … 
Could you direct me to …? 
May I ask for some help? I need to get to …? 
How can we get to High Park? 
Is it far? 
Excuse me, could you tell me how to get to the bus station? 
Go up… 
It’s on the corner 
Go straight ahead 
Cross… 
Go along… 
Turn left 
Turn right 
Turn left into … Street 
It’s in the middle of the block 
You will pass a süpermarket on your left 
Take this road 
Turn right at the crossroads 
It’s on your left 
It’s on your right 
It’s about 100 meters from here 
Take the first road on the right 
Take the second road on the left 
It’s next to… 
My body says yes, but my heart say no. 
Nope 
Maybe another time. 
I am not accepting anything else at this time. 
We appreciate the offer, but … 
I’m not really into it, but thanks for asking! 
I’d rather not, thanks. 
Nah 
That’s not going to work for me. 
Sounds fun, but I’m not available. 
I want to, but I’m unable to. 
I just don’t have that to give right now. 
I’m not able to commit to that right now. 
It is not a good idea for me. 
Apologies, but I can’t make it. 
You bring joy to my life. 
All I do is think of you. 
I love being around you. 
I’m infatuated with you. 
You crossed my mind. 
I appreciate you. 
I feel sad without you. 
You inspire me. 
You are my reason for living. 
You occupy my thoughts. 
I miss your laugh. 
I adore you. 
You’re everything to me. 
You’re the light of my life. 
I’m head over heels for you. 
I want a lifetime with you. 
Do you have a reservation? 
Do you need help with your bags? 
Is there anything else we can help you with? 
How many guests are with you? 
Your room is on the second floor. 
Thank you for staying with us! 
I’d like to book a room, please. 
We really enjoyed our stay. 
The room is too noisy. 
Can I see the room, please? 
Please sign your name here. 
More fresh towels are available at the front desk. 
I’d like a single room, please. 
Can someone help me with my bags? 
When I can check-in? 
Do you need a wake-up call?
For instance 
Additionally 
Likewise 
Note well 
As an example being… 
In particular 
Let’s say… 
This includes 
As seen in… 
E.g. 
One example is… 
Such as 
In addition to 
By way of illustration 
In a similar case 
Especially 
If you look at… 
Examples include… 
As a case in point… 
An example being… 
This can be seen when 
These include… 
As an example 
Particularly 
Like
Can you help me, please? 
Can I go out? 
Can I answer the question? 
Can I switch off the lights? 
Teacher, please can you repeat again? 
Can I open the window?
Can we pack our things now? 
What page are we on? 
I am ready. May I start it? 
What is the homework? 
Do we have to write this down? 
Sorry, for being late. 
May I open / close the window? 
Can I go to the board? 
Can I come in? 
Can I pull up the blinds? 
Can I pulldown the blinds? 
May I join the class/group? 
Can you explain it once more, please? 
May I go out please? 
Is this right? 
Is this correct? 
I am sorry. I did not hear. 
Can you speak louder, please? 
Which book? 
Can you explain that again? 
Whe is the exam? 
When is the homework for? 
I have done this. 
Can I go to the toilet? 
Good to see you 
Hey, boo 
Good evening 
Good morning 
Hello 
Hey 
How are you feeling today? 
Bonjour 
Howdy? 
How are things? 
What have you been up to? 
Look what the cat dragged in! 
It is nice to meet you 
What’s going on? 
Good afternoon. 
How have you been? 
What’s up? 
Greeting
Do you have a smaller size? 
Where is the changing room? 
Do you know where else I could try? 
Do you have this item in stock? 
Do you offer a cash discount? 
Do you have any strawberry? 
Do you have a refund policy? 
How much is this? 
Do you have a bigger size? 
Do you sell organic vegetables? 
Could you help me please? 
Where can I weight my groceries? 
Does it come with a guarantee/warranty? 
I’m looking for a leather handbag. 
Would you have this in another color? 
Do you have something less pricey (expensive)? 
Where is the fitting room? 
You’ll do great. 
Knock them dead! 
You are going to be amazing! 
Godspeed 
Wishing you all the best! 
I wish you luck! 
Best wishes. 
I hope things will turn out fine.. 
Blow them away! 
You’ll do great! 
Wishing you lots of luck! 
Fingers crossed! 
Wishing you a lot of luck! 
You were made for this! 
I hope things will work out all right. 
May the force be with you.
Much better! 
You certainly did well today. 
That kind of work makes me happy. 
Way to go. 
That’s it. 
Marvelous! 
Cool! 
Tremendous! 
Fantastic! 
Excellent! 
Super-Duper! 
Out of sight. 
Now that’s what I call a fine job. 
Couldn’t have done it better myself. 
Keep working on it; you’re improving. 
It’s such a pleasure to teach when 
You work like that! 
I think you’re doing the right thing. 
Terrific!
I see what you mean… 
So do I. 
I fee that way too. 
Definitely. 
I agree with you. 
Yup 
Yep 
Absolutely! 
You’re absolutely right. 
Exactly! 
We are of one mind. 
You can say that again. 
I could not agree with you more my friend. 
You’ve hit the nail on the head. 
You got it dude. 
Our thoughts are absolutely parallel. 
You are so right.
I shouldn’t have… 
Excuse me for… 
It’s all my fault. 
Please, accept my apologies for… 
I apologize for… 
Please, forgive me for my… 
I must apologize for… 
Ever so sory 
That’s my fault. 
Please don’t be mad at me. 
How stupid thoughtless of me. 
Please, accept my apologies for… 
I’m really ashamed of what I did. 
I’m really sorry about what I said. 
That was rude of me. I’m sorry. 
I hope you’ll forgive me for… 
I do apologize for… 
Sleep with angels 
Sleep tight, don’t let the bed bugs bite 
Let’s start counting the sheeps 
Tomorrow is not soon enough. Lets prepare. 
Time to dream 
Night night 
Nite-nite 
Have a good sleep 
Dream of me 
Until tomorrow 
Rest time for blossoms 
Don’t let the bed bugs bite! 
I’ll see you in dreamland 
Have sea dreams 
I respect you. 
You are my reason for living. 
You are precious. 
You complete me. 
You’re the love of my life. 
I can’t stop thinking about you. 
I lost my heart on you. 
You inspire me. 
I worship you. 
You are my everything. 
I need you.
I dreamt about you last night. 
You bring happiness to rainly days. 
I’ve got you under my skin. 
You are the reason I’m alive. 
You are my dear. 
I’m affectionate for you. 
I’m wild about you. 
You’re all I see. 
I want you. 
You are my reason for living. 
I lost my heart on you. 
You complete me.
That requires a bit more research first. 
Beats me. 
I don’t know anything about … 
I’m going to investigate that further. 
It’s beyond me. 
It’s a mystery to me. 
That’s a good question, but I don’t know. 
I’m not the best person to answer that. 
That’s a good question, I’II check this. 
I’m afraid. I’ve no idea. 
I can’t remember off the top of my head. 
I don’t have any information about that. 
That’s exactly what I’m seeking to answer. 
Who knows? 
Let me check on that. 
I’m not 00% sure on that. 
I’II double check and let you know. 
I quite understand. 
You couldn’t help it. 
Forget about it. 
Don’t worry about it. 
That’s all right. 
It doesn’t matter. 
Don’t worry. You’re forgiven! 
It’s ok. 
No need to… 
No harm done. 
Don’t apologize. 
Never mind. 
There’s no need to. It’s all right. 
Never mind. I quite understand. 
Forget about it. I understand. 
There is no need. It’s ok. 
Excuse me? 
Do you mind repeating that? 
Sorry, I didn’t hear what you said. 
Sorry, I didn’t catch that. 
Could you pleasse repeat that? 
Would you mind repeating that? 
Pardon? 
Sorry 
I’m hungry as a wolf! 
I’m hungry as a bear! 
Famishing 
Flying light 
Got the munchies 
Hankering 
My tummy is talking to me. 
I’m freaking hungry! 
Eager 
Greedy 
Keen 
Ravenous 
Starved 
Famished 
Hoggish 
Hollow 
I’m so hungry I could eat a scabby horse. 
Good morning, sunshine!
Morning, good looking!
Rise and shine! 
Morning! 
Wakey-wakey! 
Good day to you! 
Good morning, Sleeping beauty! 
I do apologize for… 
I must apologize for… 
Please, accept my apologies for… 
I apologize for… 
Please, forgive me for my… 
I’d like to apologize for… 
Pardon me for this… 
I am so sorry for… 